# Lluís Pellejà

# Data analyst & Data Scientist



□ lluispeso@gmail.com

**L** +34 620 301 543

# lluispelleja.com

in Lluís Pellejà

I am a highly qualified professional who's main goal is to start a new career in Switzerland as a Dat analyst or Data Scientist, the past three years I worked meanwhile I was studying my bachelor degree and my masters degree. I consider myself as a proactive person, who doesn't fear new challenges and is capable of work under pressure. I think that with my combined studies and working experience, I can contribute a lot to any company that give me the opportunity to develop my skills to another level.

## **Experience**

#### Movertis

Market Research Analyst ------ Sep 2022 - Dec 2023
In this job I have carried out the following functions:

- Create an entire app programed with Python that reduces the time consuming tasks at only one click, automatizing all the process with scrips and a machine Learning model which detects which companies have more importance for the Department of Sales.
- Create databases of target companies so that the SDR team could call the companies and generate sales opportunities.
- Analyse all data from the Sales and SDR team, to make decisions at a fast pace, justified with data. These decisions were made with the aim of achieving more sales and opportunities.

#### Movertis

Marketing & Sales Analyst ------ Jun 2021 - Aug 2022

In this job I have carried out the following functions:

- Data analysis for commercial prospecting in order to generate more sales in a more optimal way.
- Analysis of databases using technologies such as Python R and SQL in order to draw conclusions from different marketing campaigns.
- Creation of automations in Excel using Python, these automations were to generate more value by automating the most repetitive tasks and spending more time on the parts of the department that brought the most value to the business.
- Management of Pipedrive (CRM), in this task I performed dashboard maintenance and data collection, as well as data monitoring to manage the whole SDR team.
- Project management with the market research team to generate new strategies and update sales tactics to optimise efforts.

#### Movertis

Trainee Program (Marketing Analyst) ----- Mar 2021 - May 2021

In this job I have carried out the following functions:

- Market research and analysis, data collection to see the state of the company against its competitors and the market.
- Data management in CRM

## Education

#### Kschool - Master in Data Science

November 2022 - October 2023

In order to achieve the objectives and carry out the work that we are going to find as analysts, we are learning the following technologies:

- Programming in Python
- Programming in R
- Frameworks such as Kedro
- Python libraries useful for Data Science.
- Data visualization in both Python and R
- · Supervised and unsupervised learning models

## ESERP Business & Law School - International Business ----- September 2018 - June 2022

- · Business planning
- Business analysis
- Planning of real internationalization
- Adaptation of companies in different contexts
- · Analysis of different markets in the world
- · Project management in different sectors

#### Technical skills

- Python
- Scrapping web
- R
- TableauDocker
- SQL
- 1.
- ExcelGIT
- StreamlitScikit-learn
- Kedro
- RestFul-APIs
- AWS
- Pandas

## Skills

## Soft skills

- · Active listening
- · Critical thinking
- Verval & written com.
- Motivation
- · Strategic mind
- Stress management
- Logical reasoning

## Languages

Spanish (native) Catalan (native) English (fluent B2)







# **Projects**

#### PROJECT 1 - Automatization of leads generation

At this project the main goal was to create a system which can generate target companies for the Sales department in an automatic way. The pinacle of this project is that in order to extract more information it uses a machine learning model and this feature ensures the data quality of the companies.

#### PROJECT 2 - Creation of a KPI Dashboard

In this project, the main goal was to create a stable and scalable dashboard which it contains all the KPIs of the SDR team, these KPIs were from multiple platforms so the main goal was to unify the data in order to see the whole picture in one only site. Nowadays, the dashboard is self-sufficient and provides data in real time to take decisions quickly.